The Max Smith Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Max Smith Papers
1879-1933
MSS 8
Yale University Music Library
1
(4 boxes)
Correspondence, articles, and other materials by the American music critic Max Smith (1874-1935)
Smith, Max, 1874-1935
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Max Smith Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Smith's brother-in-law, James P. Atkinson, in 1950.
Arrangement
In 3 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Articles. III. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
The Max Smith Papers contain letters to and from Smith and family members, composers, performers, and critics. Arturo Toscanini is especially well represented; in particular, there are many telegrams and letters relating to Toscanini's decision to conduct the New York Philharmonic in 1926-1927, and also to the Philharmonic's European tour in 1930. The Papers also hold rough drafts and printed copies of articles by Smith. Smith's life and work are further documented by: programs; photographs; and miscellaneous materials.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Max Smith was born in New York on December 26, 1874. He received the A.B. from Yale in 1898, the same year as Charles Ives. He earned a law degree from Columbia and passed the New York bar, but never practiced. In 1909 he married Mary Hardy. They had no children. Smith studied music for many years, beginning at the age of eight; his teachers included Horatio Parker and Samuel Sanford at Yale. He served as a music editor and critic at the New York Press (1903-1916) and the New York American (1916-1919 and again in 1923). Thereafter he worked intermittently as a foreign music correspondent for the New York Herald Tribune. He died of a cerebral embolism on June 7, 1935.
Composers -- Correspondence; Conductors (Music) -- Correspondence; Music critics -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Ackté, Aino, 1876-1944; Alsen, Elsa, 1880-1975; Amato, Pasquale; Ara, Ugo, 1876-1936; Archambeau, Iwan d'; Backhaus, Wilhelm, 1884-1969; Bailly, Louis, 1882-1974; Beach, John Parsons, 1877-1953; Betti, Adolfo; Braun, Carl, 1886-1960; Busch, Adolf, 1891-1952; Campanini, Cleofonte; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968; Colonne, Edouard, 1838-1910; Conried, Heinrich, 1855-1909; Cooke, James Francis, 1875-1960; Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950; De Sabata, Victor, 1892-1967; Dippel, Johann Andreas, 1866-1932; Dohnányi, Ernő, 1877-1960; Engel, Carl, 1883-1944; Finck, Henry T., 1854-1926; Foch, Dirk, 1886-1973; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor), 1906-1981; Fremstad, Olive, -1951; Friedheim, Arthur, 1859-1932; Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936; Garden, Mary, 1874-1967; Gatti-Casazza, Giulio, 1869-1940; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962; Griffes, Charles Tomlinson, 1884-1920; Homer, Louise, 1871-1947; Hoogstraten, Willem van, 1884-1965; Huberman, Bronislaw; Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974; Hutcheson, Ernest, 1871-1951; Ives, Charles, 1874-1954; James, Philip, 1890-1975; Jeritza, Maria, 1887-1982; Kindler, Hans, 1892-1949; Knoch, Ernst, 1875-1959; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984; Koch, Caspar P. (Caspar Petrus), 1872-1970; Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967; Koshetz, Nina, 1894-1965; Le Roy, René, 1898-1985; Lockwood, Normand, 1906-2002; Marinuzzi, Gino, 1882-1945; Mario, Queena, 1896-1951; Matzenauer, Margarete, 1881-1963; Meltzer, Charles Henry, 1853-1936; Molinari, Bernardino, 1880-1952; Ney, Elly, 1882-1968; Posselt, Ruth, 1911-2007; Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953; Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943; Randegger, Giuseppe Aldo, 1874-1946; Samaroff Stokowski, Olga, 1882-1948; Saminsky, Lazare, 1882-1959; Schelling, Ernest, 1876-1939; Sembrich, Marcella, 1858-1935; Siloti, Alexander, 1863-1945; Smith, Max, 1874-1935; Spalding, Albert, 1888-1953; Spelman, Timothy Mather, 1891-1970; Telmányi, Emil; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957; Urlus, Jacques; Wagenaar, Bernard, 1894-1971; Wagner, Siegfried, 1869-1930; Wagner, Winifred
- Correspondence, 1879-1933; Series I; 3 Boxes
  General
  Correspondence is organized in the following categories:
  A. Letters to Max Smith, arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of the sender. Within each name, the letters are then placed in chronological order. Unidentified material is grouped together at the end of this section.
  B. Letters to Arthur Toscanini, arranged as above.
  C. Letters from Smith and Toscanini, arranged alphabetically by recipient. Also included in this section are letters to and from people other than Smith and Toscanini, arranged alphabetically by sender, and miscellaneous letters. Of special note is the collection of 14 copies of letters from Josef Giehrl to his parents which he wrote while studying under Liszt in Rome, 1879-1880.
  D. Telegrams mostly, and letters involved with getting Toscanini to conduct the New York Philharmonic during the 1926-1927 season. These are between (among) Toscanini, Smith, and Clarence McKay (business director for the orchestra), and are arranged chronologically from May 4, 1923 to Nov. 18, 1926. A second set of telegrams relates to the European tour of the New York Philharmonic under Toscanini, which occurred in 1930.
  E. Communiques to Messrs. Merrill and Hearst from Smith, and their answers concerning his resignation from post as Music Critic for the American paper, arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence to Max Smith, I.A
    - Ackté, Aïno, 1904; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Celesa, 1929; postcard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alsen, Elsa, 1923 Apr 28; postcard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amato, Pasquale, 1921 Aug 5; postcard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amato, Pasquale, 1922 Jun 26; no date; 2 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ara, Ugo, 1922 July -; 2 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Archambeau, Iwan d', 1926 Aug 27; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ariani, Adriano, 1917-1920; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ariani, Adriano, 1923 Jan 23; postcard (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arndt, Arthur, Thursday; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aronfreed, Mrs. Joseph, 1928 Feb 5; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Backhaus, Wilhelm, 1926 Jan 21; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bailey, Mrs. Horace, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bailly, Louis, Sunday; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Barber, Joseph, Jr., 1931 Jul 18; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beach, John [Parsons], 1931 Mar 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beddue, Mahel, 1930 Dec 2; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Berkley, Harold, 1930 Oct 27; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Betti, Adolfo, 1922; no date; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Billè, Isoia, 1921 May 18; postcard (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Blondy, Joseph, 1921 Jan 12; carbon copy (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Braun, Carl, 1929; 2 postcards (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Butler, Joseph G., 1922 Jan 4; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Busch, Adolf u. Frieda, 1931-1932; 4 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Busch, Frieda, 1932 Jan 13; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Campanini, Cleofonte, 1919 Jan 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Carriflan [?], Clarence, no date; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Caruso, Dorothy, no date; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Casals, Mrs., Dec 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cheatham, Kitty, no date; 5 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cheatham, Kitty, c1926 Dec; published song vith autograph & message (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ciampelli, Guilio Mario, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Colonne, Edouard, 1904 Nov 28; calling card (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Conried, Heinrich, 1902 Dec 26; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cooke, James Francis, 1906 Jul 31; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Copley, Richard, 1931 Jul 13; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cornu, Louis J., 1921 May 12; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Delma, D., 1921 Dec 11; postcard (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dippel, A[ndreas], 1904 Feb 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dohnanyi, [Ernö], 1931 Mar 9; telegram (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dohnanyi, [Ernö], 1923-1930; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Doodles, 1919 Feb 21; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ebert, Emilie, 1931 Jul 29; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Engel, Carl, 1931 Mar 28; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Faltis, Evelyn, 1931 Aug 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Finak, Henry T., 1925; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Flagler, Harry Harkness, 1928 Feb 4; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fleischer, Editha, 1931 Nov 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Flonzaley Quartet, 1921 Aug 22; postcard (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Foch, Dirk, 1922 Sep 10; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Frankenstein, Arthur, 1931 Nov 9; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Friedheim, Arthur, 1926 May 28; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fuiliham, J.R., 1908 Jan 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Garden, Mary, 1918 Dec 19; no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gabrilowitch, Ossip, 1931 Feb 24; telegram (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gabrilowitch, Ossip, 1926-1931; 5 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gamper, Gustav, 1928 Jun 22; postcard (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gatti-Casazza, [Giulio], 1932 Dec 31; telegram (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Goetze, Marie, 1922 Oct; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Goossens, Eugene, Thursday; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Griffes, Charles T[omlinson], 1917 Mar 13; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gruenberg, Morris, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gruesse, 1931 Dec 4; telegram (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hager, Mina, 1932 May 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hennig, [Karl Rafael], 1931 Dec 6; telegram (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hirschman, Camil [?], 1905 Feb 1; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hitchcock, Capt. Edward B., 1926 Nov 8, 10; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Holmes, Mrs. Christian R., 1931 Jul 18; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Homer, Louise, 1927-1932; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hoogstraten, Willem van, 1922 Dec 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Huberman, Bronislaw, 1923 Jan 1; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Hurok, Sol, 1928 Feb 3; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ives, Charles E[dward], 1922 Mar 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - James, Philip, 1950 Feb 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jarmel, Dorle, 1928 Mar 8; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jardon, Dorothy, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jenkins, Fred G., 1912 May 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jeritza, Maria, 1923 Nov 23; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Joe the Painter, 1922 Nov 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kindle[r], Hans, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - King, Philip A.H., 1921; 2 typed letters signed with clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knoch, Ernest, 1920 Jan 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1928 Oct 9; telegram (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kodály, [Zoltán], 1930; 2 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kohon, Benjamin, 1922 May 1; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Koshetz, Nina, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Landon, Aline, 1924 Apr 28; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - LeRoy, René, 1930 Jan 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lewis, Alessandro, 1919 Feb 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lockwood, Normand, 1929-1930; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Loelz, Sydney, 1931 Jul 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lualdi, Mie--- [?], 1926; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Luca, Giuseppe de, 1930; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - MacKay, Clarence, 3 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - MacKay, Clarence, 1928 Apr 2; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - McLellan, Eleanor, 1922 Feb 1; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marchi, Maria de, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marinuzzi, Giuseppe, 1920 Nov 13; calling card (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marinuzzi, Giuseppe, 1921 Sep 16; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mario, Queena, 1922 Dec 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Matzenauer, Margarete, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Meltzer, Charles Henry, 1905 Feb 2; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miecio, 1927; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miecio, 1928 May 18; postcard (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Münsterberg, Hugo, 1914 Dec 28; 2 typed letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Molinari, Bernardino, 1926 May; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Moor, Emanuel, 1921; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Moor, Winfred Christie, 1922-1923; 2 autograph letters signed with clipping and program (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Naguenat, Alfonse, 1919 Feb 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ney, Elly, no date; telegram (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Noble, Herbert, 1931 Aug 17; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Oldaker, Wallace J., no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Opera House Management, 1921 Mar 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Palladino, Louis, 1923 Mar 13; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Panirra [?], Tuloia, 1922 Roy 2; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Parvis, Taurino, no date; card (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Petri, Eduardo, 1932 Apr 27, 30; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1926 Jul 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1927 Jan 24; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Pochon, M., 1929 Mar 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Polaceo, Giorgio, 1919 Sep 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Polo, Enrico, 1926; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 10)
      with letter to Quinci
    - Porges, Dr. Max, 1931 Aug 3; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Posselt, Ida L. Pierce, 1923 Mar 21; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Posselt, Ruth, 1929-1932; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Price, Walter W., 1931 Apr 10; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Prokofieff, Sergei, 1930 Mar 3; postcard (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Prokofieff, Sergei and Mrs., no date; Christmas card (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Putnam, George Haven, 1914 Dec 22; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Randegger, G[iuseppe] Aldo, 1919 Apr 7; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Randegger, G[iuseppe] Aldo, 1919 Apr 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ranzow, Marie, 1931 Feb 23; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Rappoldi, Adrian, 1928 Jun 15; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - René, Anna Eld...[?], 1920 Jan 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Rosensten, Arthur, 1918 May 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ruysd..l [?], 1912 Apr 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sabata, Victor de, 1926 Sep 14; card (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sabata, Victor de, no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Saminsky, Lazare, 1931 Apr 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Scandini, Angelo, 1921 Mar 26; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Scandini, Angelo, no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schelling, Ernest, 1931 Apr 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schlegel, Carl, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schrader, Frederick Franklin, 1919 Mar 16; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schreiner, George, 1926 Jun 9; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Schumann, Elisabella Purity, 1915 Jun 5; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sibella, Gabriele, no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Siloti, Alexander, no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Siloti, Alexander, 1922 Jun 25; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Skraup, Dr. Siegmund, 1931 Aug 29; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sorrentino, Umberto, 1921 Apr 1; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sorrentino, Umberto, 1921 May 10; card (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Spalding, Albert, Oct 22; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Spaulding, Mrs. W.F., 1905 Feb 13; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Speed, [?], 1928 Sep 14; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Spelman, Timothy, 1928-1929; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Spencer, Eleanor, 1919 Mar 4; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stokowski, Olga Samaroff, 1926 Feb 17; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stone, Matja, 1922 Mar 28; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sylva, Marguerita, no date [1920]; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sylva, Marguerita, 1920 Oct 6; carbon copy (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Telmanyi, Emil, 1920 Jun 20; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thode, Daniela, 1931 Oct 6; postcard (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thode, Daniela, 1932 Mar 2; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thode, Daniela, 1932 Nov 7; telegram (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tinty, Baronin Adelma, no date; calling card (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Titherington, R.H., 1928 Sep 14; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tournilles, H. Chardon, 1930 Mar 9; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Toscanini, Arturo, 1913 Dec 28; no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Toscanini, Arturo, 1922-1932; 11 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Universal Edition, 1931 Jun 8; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Urlus, Jacques, 1923 Mar 14; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wagenaar, Bernard, 1931 Jan 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wagner, Siegfried, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wagner, Winifred, 1931 Jun 11; typed letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wagner, Winifred, 1933 Apr 25; telegram (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Weisbach, Hugo, 1931 Jul 11; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Weldon, Henry, 1919 Jan 24; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Williams, F[rederic Arthur], 1905 Feb 18; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - unidentifiable, 1927-1932; no date; 9 autograph letters signed, 2 postcards, 1 photocopy, 1 autograph (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence to Toscanini, I.B
    - Butler, Nicholas, 1931; 2 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Artie Mason, 1930 Jul 26; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1933 Feb 2; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Damrosch, Walter, 1928 Feb 27; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Drysdale, J. Kennedy, 1930 Jul 1; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fischer, J., 1933 Mar 13; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fremstad, Olive, 1931 Dec 12; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fry, Martin, 1930 Aug 18; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hutcheson, Ernest, 1930 Mar 31; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Isaacson, Charles D., 1928 Mar 21; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Juenger, Adolf, 1931 Dec 13; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Knopfmacher, Siegfried, no date; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Koch, Caspar, 1930 Dec 16; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Kraus, Geb., 1929 Mar 29; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Lampe, Ewald, 1930 Aug 19; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Lindsay, George F., 1927-1928; 2 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mackay, Clarence, 1928 Feb; typed letter (Box 2, Folder 2)
      with typed letter from Toscanini dealing with same
    - Mackay, Clarence, 1929 Oct 24; telegram (Box 2, Folder 2)
      with note from Toscanini on reverse side
    - Meyer, Hans u. Eule, 1930 Aug 20; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Nevils, W. Coleman, 1930 Mar 28; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Saminsky, Lazare, 1931; no date; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sembrich, Marcella, 1932 Nov 29; telegram (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Smith Max, 1924; typed letter (rough draft) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Smith Max, 1933; copies of 2 telegrams (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Veiga, Dr. Angel, 1928 Feb 3; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Wagner, Winifred, 1930 Aug 19; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Wagner, Winifred, 1931; 3 telegrams (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Wiener Philharmonischer, Feb 16; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - unidentified, 4 autograph letters signed, 2 typed letters signed (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Smith and Toscanini, I.C
    - From Smith
      - To Sergei Radamsky, 1931 Apr 12; typed letter (copy) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - To Winifred Wagner, 1931-1933; 3 telegrams (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - From Toscanini
      - To Walter Damrosch, 1928 Mar 1; typed letter (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - To Herr Fries, no date; typed letter (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - To Mr. Jaenicke, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - To and from others
      - From Margorie Betrick to H.M. Roberts, no date; typed letter (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - From Maria Jeritza to H.M. Roberts, no date; typed letter (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - From John Martin to Sarah D. Lowrie, 1927 Sep 12; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - From F. Warndof to Mr. Gershwin, 1929 Oct 10; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - From Chicago Opera Association to Max Smith, 1919 Jan 3; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - To [Smith?] from Joseph Stransky, 1918 Apr 2; carbon copy (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - From West Side YMCA to Max Smith, 1914 Mar 5; typed letter signed (Box 2, Folder 6)
        (with notes on blank part of letter)
      - From Josef Giehrl to his parents, written while a pupil of Liszt's in Rome, 1879-1880; 14 copies of typed letters (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence Relating to Toscanini and the New York Philharmonic, I.D
    - Exchange of correspondence among Toscanini, Smith, and Mackay concerning Toscanini's coming to America to conduct the New York Philharmonic, 1923 May 4-1926 Nov 18; 64 telegrams, 9 typed letters signed, 6 carbon copies of typed letters (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - Concerning the New York Philharmonic's tour of Europe with Toscanini, 1930 Apr 23-1930 Oct 9; 26 telegrams (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      (mostly from Mackay to Smith)
  - Correspondence relating to Smith's resignation from The New York American, I.E
    - Copies of letters by Max Smith to, and letters from Mr. Merrill and Mr. Hearst about Max's job as Music Critic, 12 typed letters (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Articles, 1922-1923; no date; Series II; 1 Box
  The articles in this section are mostly typed rough drafts of newspaper articles, organized as follows:
  A. Articles by Max Smith on Toscanini, reviews and criticisms of operas and singers, and critical reviews of miscellaneous concerts, arranged by topic